Guide to the Richard Bonelli Collection
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
Richard Bonelli Collection
1911-1986
ARS-0005
RIchard Bonelli
Mona Modini Bonelli
22 linear feet
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound Stanford University Libraries Stanford, California 94305-3076
The collection consists of Bonelli's letters, documents, photographs, programs, publications, scores, scrapbooks, audiovisual materials, posters and newspaper clippings.
Access
Collection is open for research. Listening appointments may require 24 hours notice. Contact the Archive Operations Manager.
Biography / Administrative History
Baritone Richard Bonelli was born Richard Bunn in Port Byron, New York on Feb. 2, 1889. His voice teachers were Arthur Alexander in Los Angeles, and Jean de Reszke and William Valonat in Paris. His operatic debut was as Valentin in Gounod's Faust at the Brooklyn Academy in 1915. From 1922-24 he toured the U.S. with the San Carlo opera company. After touring in Europe with the Max Sauter Company in 1925, he was engaged at the Theatre Gaite Lyrique in Paris. That same year he was to join the Chicago Opera Company, remaining there until 1931. Between 1926 and 1942 he was a frequent guest at the San Francisco Opera, and was also a member of the Metropolitan Opera from 1932-45. After retiring from the stage he dedicated himself to voice pedagogy and was a much-appreciated teacher. He taught at the Curtis Institute of Music in Philadelphia, and at the Music Academy of the West. Richard Bonelli died in Los Angeles on June 7, 1980.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection includes several hundred personal and business letters; documents ranging from private matters, such as his divorce papers from his first wife Pauline Curley, to professional matters, such as his multiple opera contracts; photographs from his childhood and family, a large number of promotional portrait photographs, some featuring him in costume for various opera roles; a collection of programs; publications, mainly dealing with opera companies; annotated opera vocal scores and songs; seven scrapbooks containing mainly newspaper clippings; audiovisual materials; testimonials; and posters and newspaper clippings.
Arrangement
Series 1. Correspondence. 2. Documents. 3. Photographs. 4. Programs. 5. Publications. 6. Scores. 7. Scrapbooks. 8. Publications. 9. Films. 10. Sound recordings. 11. Testimonials and awards. 12. Posters and snakes. 13. News clippings. 14. Miscellany.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Bonelli, Richard; Bonelli, Mona Modini; Opera; Baritones (Singers)
Container List
- Correspondence
  - 1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1913 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1914 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1918 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1919 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1920 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1921 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1922 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1923 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1924 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1925 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1926 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1927 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1928 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1929 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1930 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1931 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - 1932 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - 1933 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - 193? (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1935 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Martin Bunn 1898 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Mona Bonelli 1931-1933 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Jones and Blakeslee 1959-1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1925-1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1941-1953 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1955-1983 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Henry Jaffe 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - W.R. Moran and Eduard E. Colby 1963-1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fan letters 1932-1945 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Town Hall Recital, Feb. 5, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Columbia Concerts Co. Concert Management Arthur Judson 1930-1933 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Columbia Concerts Co. Concert Management Arthur Judson 1934-1936 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Columbia Concerts Co. Concert Management Arthur Judson 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Columbia Concerts Co. Concert Management Arthur Judson 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Leigh Bureau of Lectures and Entertainments 1943-1945 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Leigh Bureau of Lectures and Entertainments Jan-July 1946 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Leigh Bureau of Lectures and Entertainments 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Wolfsohn Musical Bureau of N. Y. 1928-1931 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - National Concert and Artists Corp. 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Celebrity Artists Corp. 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Edward S. Smith 1947-1955 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Opera Co. 1940-1948 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The City of Music and Drama 1946-1954 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Detroit Civic Opera Society 1934 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Empire State Music Festival 1955-1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - San Francisco Opera Association 1932-1940 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Hollywood Bowl Association 1926-1948 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Metropolitan Opera Association 1935-1945 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Metropolitan Opera Quartet 1934 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The National Council of the Metropolitan Opera 1958-1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - New Orleans Opera 1937-1938 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Seattle Opera and The Cornish School 1961-1963 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The Waltz King 1944 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - The Curtis Institute 1941-1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The Curtis Institute 1951-1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Music Academy of the West 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Music Academy of the West 1948 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Music Academy of the West 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Auditions 1948-1969 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Music and Arts Institute of San Francisco 1951-1953 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Masterclass, University of Utah 1956 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Washington State Music Teachers Association 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Moving Pictures 1934-1949 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - NBC Artists Service 1940-1942 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Documents
  - Diplomas (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Syracuse HIgh School diploma June 22, 1906; Academic diploma. University of the State of New York. Jan. 21, 1907; University of Syracuse honorary Doctorate in Music. May 31, 1937
  - Date books, 1911-1914 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Biography, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Divorce from Pauline Curley, 1933-1952 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Marriage License, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Lists of films and sound recordings (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - List of movies, records, air checks (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Lists of movies, records, air-checks (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Binder for lists (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Performances with Chicago Opera Company, 1925-1931 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Itineraries and performances, 1927-1937 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Opera, concert and radio broadcast announcements (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Promotional leaflets (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Announcement for opera lecture (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Radio scripts, 1934-1941 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Radio scripts: Universal Rhythms April 17 - July 11, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Radio scripts: Universal Rhythms July 18 - Sept. 5, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Financial (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Travel bills (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Receipts, 1935-1948 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Real estate, Sunset Strip lot, 1941-1946 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Renter's lease, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Opera and concert contracts, 1923-1935 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Opera and concert contracts, 1936-1946 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - The National Committee for the Musical Arts, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Excerpts from press notices (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Metropolitan Opera Farewell, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Awards (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Elinor Remick Warrer, Metropolitan Opera accompanist (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - The recordings of Titta Ruffo - a discography (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Eulogy to Rudolph Valentino, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Notes for a talk? (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - International Record Collector's Club, publicity sheet ,1966 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Photocopies of opera book (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Syracuse University. Alumni Glee Club, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - List of recordings (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Lists of invitations sent (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Recording companies promotional leaflets (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Photographs
  - Richard Bonelli alone (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Richard Bonelli alone (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Richard Bonelli alone (duplicates) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Richard Bonelli alone (duplicates) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Richard Bonelli alone. Kriegsman, photographer (duplicates) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Richard Bonelli alone. Kriegsman, photographer (duplicates) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aïda, as Amonasaro (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Ballo in maschera, as Renato (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Barbiere di Siviglia, as Figaro (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Bohème, as Marcello (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Carmen, as Escamillo (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust, as Valentin (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Scenen aus Göthe's Faust, as Faust (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900. Gondoliers, as Giuseppe Palmieri (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Hérodiade, as Herod (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Lucia di Lammermoor, as Henry Ashton (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Nozze di Figaro, as Conte Almaviva (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Lustige Witwe, as Count Danilo (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900. Mikado, as Ko-Ko (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Franchetti, Aldo. Namiko San, as Daymio (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Otello, as Iago (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Pagliacci, as Tonio (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Don Pasquale, as Malatesta (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Rigoletto, as Rigoletto (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Snegurochka, as Mizgir' (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser, as Wolfram (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Puccini, Giacomo, 1858-1924. Tosca, as Scarpia (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata, as Germont (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tristan und Isolde, as Kurneval (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore, as Conte di Luna (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Duplicates (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Duplicates (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Duplicates (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Negatives (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Bonelli with one other person (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Bonelli with several people (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Family (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Italy, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Baden-Baden (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Central City, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Broadcasting (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - G.E. Encampment (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - River Ronge Plant and Greenfield Village, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Bonelli with his Great Dane (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Music Academy of the West, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Duplicates (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Programs
  - Undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1909-1933 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1934-1937 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1938-1942 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1943-1963 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Carbon copies, machine typed (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - 1909-1931 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1932-1936 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - 1937-1938 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - 1942-1983 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Publications
  - Boston National Opera Co. and Boston Theater Opera Co. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - San Carlo Opera Co. Vol. I, 1913-1936 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - San Carlo Opera Co. Vol. II, 1936 -1955 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - San Carlo Opera Co. 1913 -1955 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles Opera Association, 1924 - 1934 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Scotti Grand Opera Co. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Periodical: 1941; 1943; 1976; 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Il Teatro, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Curtis Institute, 1953 - 1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The World's Finest Radio (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Syracuse University Alumni News and Bulletin, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Variety; News of the Show World, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Opera libretti (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - A century of the Met; At the Met, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Scores
  - Cilèa, Francesco, 1866-1950. Adriana Lecouvreur (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Delibes, Léo, 1836-1891. Lakmé (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Donizetti, Gaetano, 1797-1848. Don Pasquale (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Février, Henry, 1875-1957. Monna Vanna. Dis-la vite (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Flotow, Friedrich, Freiherr von, 1812-1883. Martha oder: Der Markt zu Richmond. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Sullivan, Arthur, Sir, 1842-1900. Mikado (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948. Andrea Chénier (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Giordano, Umberto, 1867-1948. Cena delle beffe (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Humperdinck, Engelbert, 1854-1921. Hansel and Gretel (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Leoncavallo, Ruggiero, 1858-1919. Zazà (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912. Manon (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Montemezzi, Italo, 1875-1952. Amore dei tre re (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Moret, Ernest. Lorenzaccio (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Nozze di Figaro (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Paisiello, Giovanni, 1740-1816. Barbiere di Siviglia (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Petrella, Errico, 1813-1877. La contessa d'Amalfi (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Ponchielli, Amilcare, 1834-1886. Gioconda (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Barbiere di Siviglia (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Strauss, Johann, 1804-1849. Fledermaus (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Mignon (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Aïda (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Ballo in maschera (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Traviata (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Trovatore (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Lohengrin (duplicate) (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Grainger, Percy, 1882-1961. Tribute to Foster (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Händel, Georg Friedrich, 1685-1759. Messiah. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Harty, Hamilton, Sir, 1879-194. Mystic Trumpeter (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Elias (Theodor Presser,publisher) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Elias (Novello & Co., publisher) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Weinberg, Jacob, 1879-1956. Gettysburg address (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Spanish choral ballads. Sacred and secular Catalonian folk music (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Golde, Walter, 1887-1963. Offering (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Harling, W. Franke (William Franke), 1887-1958. Requiem (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Lester, Edwin. Faust-Carmen (manuscript) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Vocal album (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Opera selections (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Belonging to Mamie Perry
  - Miscellaneous works bound together (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Cover inscribed: Mona Modini
  - Scottish Airs (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Collection of German songs (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Covers inscribed: Richard Bonelli. Collection reflects original order. Contains published scores and manuscripts. Balogh, Ernö 1897-, Lieder. Ket Enek. (Vienna: Universal Edition, c1930); Lieder. Harom Enek. (Vienna: Universal Edition, c1930) -- Bruch, Max, 1838-1920. Songs. Maiden fair and sparkling. Op.97, No.5 (Boston: Carl Fischer, c1921) -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Selected Songs. Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht. (New York: Luckhardt & Belder) -- Dvorák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Gems of German Song. Vnárodním tónu. Dobrú noc, má milá. (New York: G. Schirmer, c1891) -- Franz, Robert, 1815-1892. Ausgewählte Lieder. (Leipzig: C.F.W. Siegel) -- Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907. Selected songs. Zickeltanz. (New York: G. Schirmer, c1902) -- Henschel, Georg, Sir, 1850-1934. Deutscher Liederverlag. Ballade von Felix Dahn. (Berlin: Breitkopf & Härtel) -- Kodály, Zoltán, 1882-1967. Psalmus Hungaricus. (Vienna: Universal Edition, c1928)-- Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Eternal. (New York: M. Witmark & Sons, c1937) -- Mahler, Gustav, 1860-1911. Selections. Knaben Wunderhorn. Revelge. (Leipzig: C.F. Kahnt, c1905); Lieder und Gesänge. (Leipzig: Edition B. Schott); 12 Gesänge aus Des Knaben Wunderhorn. (Vienna: Universal Edition) -- Marx, Joseph, 1882-1964. Lieder und Gesänge. Hat dich die Liebe berührt. (manuscript); Ton. (Vienna: Universal Edition, c1911) -- Mattiesen, Emil, 1875-1939. Heitere Lieder. Huhn und der Karpfen. (Leipzig: C.F. Peters) -- Rubinstein, Anton, 1829-1894. Dew is Sparkling. (manuscript); Dew is Sparkling. (New York: G. Schirmer, c1879) -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Deutscher Liederverlag. An die Musik. (Leipzig, Breitkopf & Härtel); Lieder und Gesänge. Pastorella al prato. (Song) (Berlin: Rob. Lienau) -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Selections. Sängers Fluch. Provenzalisches Lied. (New York: Carl Fischer, c1913); Selected Songs. Romanzen und Balladen, op. 49. Beiden Grenadiere. (New York: G. Schirmer, c1910); Lieder und Gesänge, op. 77. Aufträge. (manuscript) -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 29. Nachtgang. (Vienna: Universal Edition, c1897); Winterliebe. (London: Adolf Fürstner Limited, c1901); Lieder, op. 27. Cäcilie. (Vienna: Universal Edition, c1896) -- Weingartner, Felix, 1863-1942. Gedichte, op. 16. Liebesfeier. (manuscript) -- Wolff, Erich J. (Erich Jaques), 1874-1913. Songs. Selections. Ich bin so allein. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1939); Die Ganze Welt mit all ihrem Glanz. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1939); Gottes Garten. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1939); Seit du da bist. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1939); Von Herz zu Herz. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1939); Erinnerung. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1939); Erntefest. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1939); Melodien. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1940); Liebe mich. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1940); Schlafe ruhig ein. (New Jersey: Harmonia, c1939); Märchen.(Berlin: Ed. Bote & G. Bock, c1913); Ewig. (Leipzig: C.F. Kahnt, c1913); Fäden. (Berlin: Harmonie, c1907); Bekenntnis. (manuscript)
  - Collection of Spanish songs (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Covers inscribed: Richard Bonelli. Collection reflects original order. Contains published scores and manuscripts. Alvarez, F. M. (Fermín María), 1833-1898. Amor y Olvido (manuscript); Canto del Presidiario (Madrid: Unión Musical Española) -- Arniches y Barrera, Carlos, 1866-1943. Granadinas de la Zarzuela. Emigrantes (Madrid: Faustino Fuentes) -- Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Amor brujo (London: J & W. Chester, LTD., c1922) -- Font, Manuel. Cruz de Mayo. (Habana: Excelsior Music Co.) -- Freire, Osman Perez, 1878-1930. Ay, ay, ay. (manuscript); Celebre Cancão Creoula. Ay, ay, ay. (New York: R.L. Huntzinger, Inc., c1921) -- García, Manuel, 1775-1832. Polo en Criado fingido (Madrid: A. Romero)-- Granados, Enrique, 1867-1916. Canción del postillón (New York: G. Schirmer, c1916) -- Grever, María, 1885-1951. Recuerdos. (New York: G. Schirmer, c1930)-- Islas, Jose. Yo paso la vida. (New York: G.Ricordi & Co. c1926) -- Lecuona, Ernesto, 1896-1963. A Nena Plana. Canto Siboney. (Habana: Lecuona Music Co.) -- Padilla, José, 1889-1960. Relicario. Célebre Couplet. (Habana: Anselmo Lopez y Cia.) -- Panganucci, Anthony F. Il Gitano Re (New York: Carl Fischer, c1928) -- Ponce, Manuel M. (Manuel María), 1882-1948. Estrellita (New York: G. Ricordi & Co., Inc., c1923) -- Rubertis, Víctor de. Brindis de Amor. (manuscript) --Simon, Edward G. Querida. (New York: Car Fischer, c1928) -- Williams, Alberto, 1862-1952. Canciones incáicas, op. 45. Vidalita. (Buenos Aires: Gurina y Cia.) -- Yradier, Sebastián, 1809-1865. Paloma. (Boston: Oliver Ditson Co., c1911) Songs of the Pyrenees with Spanish, French and English words (Boston: Arthur P. Schmidt, c1877) -- trad. Cielito Lindo. (New York: G. Ricordi & Co., Inc., c1930); Paloma. (New York: G. Ricordi & Co., Inc., c1927); Flores de España. Pregúntales a las estrellas. (Boston: Oliver Ditson Co., c1922); Mexican Songs. Pregúntales a las estrellas. (New York: G. Ricordi & Co., c1922)
  - Collection of English songs I (Box 24, Folder 10)
    Covers inscribed: Richard Bonelli. Collection reflects original order. Contains published scores and manuscripts. Bacon, Ernst, 1898-, Songs from the American folk. Lonesome grove (New York: C. Fischer, c1946) -- Bohm, Carl, 1844-1920. German Songs. Stille wie die Nacht (Boston: B. F. Wood Music Co.) -- Campbell - Tipton. Rhapsodie, Op. 32, No.1(New York: G. Schirmer, c1913); Spirit Flower (New York: G. Schirmer, c1908) -- Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Lousiana (New York: Galaxy Music Corporation, c1940) -- Charles, Ernest, 1895-1984. Sweet song of long ago (New York: G. Schirmer, c1933) -- Coates, Eric, 1886-1957. Music of the night (New York: Chappell - Harms Inc., c1934) -- Coleridge, Samuel Taylor, 1772-1834. Life and Death (London: Augener Ltd., c1914); Onaway, awake, beloved (London: Novello & Co., Ltd., c1898) -- Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934. Sea pictures. (London: Boosey & Co., Ltd. c1899) -- Engel, Carl, 1818-1882. Lyrics. Sea Shell (New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., c1911) -- Fox, Oscar J., 1879-1961. O perfect love (New York: Carl Fischer, Inc., c1946) -- Gabrilowitsch, Ossip, 1878-1936. Songs. Near to thee. (New York: Carl Fischer, Inc., c1924) -- Giannini, Vittorio, 1903-1966. Poems of the sea. Song of the albatross. (New York: G. Ricordi & Co., Inc., c1935); Sea Dream. (New York: G. Ricordi & Co., Inc., c1935) -- Golde, Walter, 1887-1963. Low blowing winds. (New York: Galaxy Music Corporation, c1938) -- Grant Still, William. Plain chant for America. (New York: J. Fischer & Bro., c1941) -- Griffes, Charles Tomlinson, 1884-1920. Poems by John Masefield. Old song re-sung (New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., c1920) -- Hageman, Richard, 1882-1966. Selections. Sundown. (New York: Carl Fischer, c1938); Little things. (New York: Galaxy Music Corporation, c1943); Music I heard with you (New York: Galaxy Music Corporation, c1938); Rich man (New York: Galaxy Music Corporation, c1937) -- Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Mistress mine. Music from Jephtha. (New York: Patersons Publications Ltd., c1927) -- Hely-Hutchinson, Victor, 1901-1947. Rolling English Road. (London: Elkin & Co. Ltd., c1933); Old mother Hubbard (New York: Carl Fischer, c1929) -- Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Ballads. Belle Dame sans Merci (New York: Associated Music Publishers, Inc., c1945) -- Diack, Michael J. Little Jack Horner. A new setting of an old rhyme. (London: Paterson's Publications Ltd., c1936) -- Jacobson, Myron K. Selections. Nature Mourns. (Boston: Oliver Ditson Co., c1917); Last love, Op.20, No.1. (New York: Carl Fischer, c1925); Midsummer night. (New York: Carl Fischer, c1925) -- Kernochan, Marshall, 1880-1955. Smuggler's song. (New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., c1911); Love song of Har Dyal, Op.12, No.2. (Boston: Oliver Ditson Co., c1917) -- Kountz, Richard, 1896-1950. Sleigh. (New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., c1926) -- Kramer, Warren Alvin, 1897-, Swans. (New York: G. Ricordi & Co., Inc., c1917) -- Simon, Edward G. Querida. (New York: Carl Fischer, c1928) -- Smith, Alice Mary, 1839-1884. O, that we two were maying. (New York: G. Schirmer, Inc.) -- Smith, Kenneth Leslie, 1946-, Salt Water. (New York: Boosey & Hawkes, Inc., c1936) -- Templeton, Alec, 1910-1963. Songs. Longing. (New York: G. Schirmer, Inc., c1937) -- Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958. Songs of travel. (London: Boosey & Co., c1905); On Wenlock edge. (London: Boosey & Co., c1911) -- Walton, Kenneth, 1904-1986. Song of sleep. (New York: Sprague-Coleman, c1937); Ship for Singapore. (New York: Chappell-Harms Inc., c1935) -- Whelpley, Benjamin, 1864-1946. Songs from Tennyson's Maud. (New York: G. Schirmer, c1906) -- Wragg, Russel, 1899-, Selections. Little Towns (New York: R. L. Huntzinger, Inc., c1938); Plantation Plaint. (New York: G. Schirmer, c1937); Papa sings. (New York: Schroeder & Gunther, Inc., c1935); My heart remembers. (New York: R. L. Huntzinger, Inc., c1938); Lilacs. (New York: R. L. Huntzinger, Inc., c1937); Song of work. (New York: G. Schirmer, c1936)